If your father is from any type of family
and you are troubled by the insurance company, then
this video is for you. Yes friends,
hello, welcome to the Open Online Service.
In this video, we are going to tell you
how to file an online complaint with IRDA. They have a website called
IG Haste A, which means
Integrated Cross Management System, where
if the policy holder has any kind
of problem, he can go there and
file an online complaint. The policy holder
can also file a complaint against the insurance company or the exit gate branch. It is
quite a great tool, so if you have any
kind of problem, then with the
help of this video of ours, you can definitely file a complaint and
your complaint will
definitely be resolved there. Earlier,
I had made a video in which I have told you about many ways to complain to the insurance company. If
you
want to watch this video, you
can watch it and let us tell you the complete step by step
details of how to file an online complaint. If you have
come to our channel for the first time, please subscribe to our channel
and also get information about insurance
companies.  To complain against, you will have to
go to the official website of the exam IG ma.ar gov.in. So
here first of all if you have
come for the first time then you have to register here,
here your basic details will be asked
like your name, date of birth, gender,
PAN number, your address, so enter these details and
save it and register yourself,
now enter the ID here and
you can log in with the same, after that now
we will log in here and tell you, so
you can log in with all the things which
you have used while registering, so now
we will enter the PAN card, now you will
log in by entering your PAN card and date of birth here, now
here you have to write your date of
birth in DD and BDY, if
MAM means Monday then you will
write Young Monday, if it is December then you will
write DC, you have to write in this way, you will log
in, as soon as you log in, the
details of the complaint you have made will be visible here, in this way the
details of the complaint you have made will be visible here
Here in David, you
can see in detail what is the status of your complaint,
what message was given in its closure,
you will get all these things here.
Now to make a new complaint, click on the
registration Great Scientist option inside the complaint.
See, here you will
see three options above. First,
if you have life insurance, then select the first option.
If you do
not have life insurance, then select this Baba option.
If you have agriculture
insurance related to agriculture, then
click on the third option.
Now select life insurance to show you.
After that you will be asked against
whom you
want to complain. Insurance broker. There are many company agents in the middle.
Unregistered agents mean that the person against whom you want to
complain is
not registered. The intermediary is someone else. Usually,
our complaint is
against the insurance company. Many times it is
also against the broker. There are very less chances that
you will take action against a third party. It can be
anyone. So, right now we are going to file these complaints.
After entering several, you have to
select the name of the company
against which you
want to complain. You will get a list here.
You can select any company from here
with which you have life insurance. So, right now, to
show you, we have
selected Bajaj. After that, you have to
select the branch. As soon as you
click on the search here, a window will
open like this. Here you can write the
branch name according to the state, district, city, pin code. If you know it, then search. If
not, then you can find it for the entire state together. From
here, you will
select the branch. For example, I have
selected Indore. The branch
code will appear there. After that, the policy type. Now, is your
policy conventional? Is it a life insurance
policy? Is it a health insurance policy? Is it a
pension policy? Is it unit linked or other?
If you belong to any of these categories,
select it. Otherwise, if you do
not know, then we will
enter conventional here. After that, you have to select the complaint
tile. Now, complaint by step, here you have to
select it.  Survival claim, death claim, under
business practice, policy servicing
or proposal processing, these options will be there,
you have to use them, otherwise you can do it,
many people face problem in death claim,
some
also face problem in servicing of the policy, many people face problem
in proposal, so you will choose one here,
after that the next option will be
activated, now
here you can see survivor claim, now so
many options have come, surrender value not made,
your concern regarding surrender value,
maturity claim not, so whatever your
problem is here, you can see it
carefully from here and select it from here, then
we enter it, I am not
clear now after that you have to enter
your college number here, you have entered the number from the call,
you have entered your policy bond or your insurance
premium from there, you will see it from there,
grandmother will enter that number here,
enter the date from when your policy has been active, whatever data you have, you will
select it here, then enter the amount which will be the
previous amount, now see
here if group insurance  If it has happened then
you will dip it here, the proposal number will be
filled here, the first option is mandatory, the rest
are optional, if there is a detail then put it, if it is not there then do
not put it, after that here you have to
write the details in the additional information, so in this way you will
write the complaint completely, here I
cannot tell you that every policy holder
's problem is different, how to
write it, but you have to keep it in two that
all your points should be very precise and
you should write clearly in two-three points
what is your problem, think you have
deposited all the premiums on time,
even after that you are not getting the maturity benefit
which was promised or there is some other
problem, it is totally a different policy
holder, so you have to write it here, after that you have to
submit it, see
after joining in this way, you will
go to complaint here, in this way you will
get the token number and your complaint will be
visible, go to Be Wise, then
when your complaint gets updated, then
see when you see the status  If you check, then the
status will show you that the
complaint has been registered in the portal or the
knowledge has been maintained, after that the policy was checked here
and the solution was given in this way, the
complaint was closed,
see after filing the complaint, there is a long
time for closure within which the insurance company will have to
attend to your problem and
here you will have to give the solution, as soon as the solution
comes, if you are not satisfied with it, then this
option of this plate will be visible, you will
select this, then your complaint will
go to IRDA, due to which it will be reviewed
and action will be taken on your complaint again, so if
you liked that video, do
tell us through comment, we will meet
with a new video, till then bye-bye